这是双子座五号的探测报告，舰长
Here's the report on Pollux V, captain.
整个星系都基本一致
This entire system has been almost the same.
出乎意料的缺少智慧生物
A strange lack of intelligent life on the planets.
这与统计数据不符
It bucks the percentages.
随它去吧
Bucks them.
好吧，对双子座四号进行标准探测程序
Well, carry out the standard procedures on Pollux IV.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
上尉，你今天早上看起来有些疲倦
Lieutenant, you look a bit tired this morning.
是啊，我整晚都在准备这份报告
Well, I was up all night working on this report.
这样的话，没什么比喝点咖啡更好的了
In that case, there's nothing like a wee bit of coffee to get you back in shape.
- 一起去吧，卡洛琳 - 好吧，史考特
- Join me, Carolyn? - All right, Scotty.
让我先把这个交给史波克先生
Just let me give this to Mr. Spock.
老骨头
Bones,
你会因为一杯咖啡就那么兴奋吗？
could you get that excited over a cup of coffee?
从这儿我都能感觉他心跳加速了
Even from here, I can tell his pulse rate's up.
先生们
Gentlemen.
这边请，亲爱的
Come along, my dear.
我不确定我喜欢这种情况，吉姆
I'm not sure I like that, Jim.
老骨头，为什么？史考特是个好人
Why, Bones? Scotty's a good man.
并且他觉得他是她的真命天子
And he thinks he's the right man for her,
但是我不确定她也是这么想的
but I'm not sure she thinks he's the right man.
从另一方面来讲，她是个女人，跟所有女人一样
On the other hand, she's a woman. All woman.
总有一天，她会找到她喜欢的那个人，然后她就会离开他
One day, she'll find the right man. Off she'll go, out of the service.
相比失去下属，我更愿意把这当成是获得…
I like to think of it not so much as losing an officer as gaining...
这边请
Come along.
是啊，我正在失去一名下属
Actually, I'm losing an officer.
正在进入双子座四号的标准轨道，长官
Entering standard orbit around Pollux IV, sir.
- 图像细节，准备 - 已准备好，长官
- Cartographic details. Stand by. - Standing by, sir.
初始报告，史波克先生
Preliminary reports, Mr. Spock.
双子座四号，M级别星球，氮氧大气层
Pollux IV. Class-M type planet. Oxygen-nitrogen atmosphere.
探测器显示无生命迹象
Sensors indicate no life forms.
大约年龄：40亿年 结论：无需接触
Approximate age: Four billion years. Judged: No reason for contact.
综合考虑，很普通的星球，舰长
In all respects, quite ordinary, captain.
制图部门，进行标准程序
Cartographic sections, implement standard orders.
所有制图扫描器，自动运行
All cartographic scanners, full automatic.
舰长
Captain.
这是什么？
What in the name of?
- 分析报告，史波克先生 - 马上就好
- Analysis, Mr. Spock. - Momentarily.
我产生幻觉了吗？
Am I seeing things?
除非我也一样
Not unless I am too.
舰长，那是一只巨大的手
Captain, that thing's a giant hand.
那是什么，史波克先生？难道是…
What is it, Mr. Spock? Is it...
一只手？
...a hand?
不是，舰长，不是生物组织
Negative, captain. Not living tissue.
那就是玩的戏法，是投影吗？
A trick, then. A projection?
不是投影，长官，是一种能量
Not a projection, sir. A field of energy.
- 紧急绕开 - 紧急绕开
- Hard about. - Hard about.
看样子我们躲不开了
We can't seem to get away from it.
就像是它故意要抓住我们一样
It's almost as if it means to grab us.
- 反转所有引擎 - 所有引擎，反转
- Reverse all engines. - All engines, reverse.
我们不能动了，舰长
We're dead still, captain.
防护罩没有反应，我们不能动了
Helm doesn't answer. We can't move.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：刘诗濛
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第二集
诸神哀歌
舰长日记，星历3468.1
Captain's log, stardate 3468.1.
当逼近位于双子座星系的第四颗行星时
While approaching Pollux IV, a planet in the Beta Geminorum system,
进取号被一种未知能量
the Enterprise has been stopped in space
困在了太空中
by an unknown force of some kind.
上尉
Lieutenant,
把我们的位置和情况马上报告给太空站12号
relay our position and circumstances to Starbase 12 immediately.
- 是，长官 - 苏鲁先生
- Aye, aye, sir. - Mr. Sulu.
试试晃动飞船
Try rocking the ship.
全负荷脉冲能量，往前再往后
Full impulse power, forward and back.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
损伤报告出来了，舰长，尚在可控范围
Damage report coming in, captain. Situation under control.
站台3、7、19，小范围损伤
Minor damage, Stations 3, 7 and 19.
医疗站有5个轻伤，全都在治疗中
Sickbay reports five minor injuries. All being treated.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 苏鲁先生？ - 启动脉冲引擎，长官
- Mr. Sulu? - Applying thrust, sir.
没有效果，舰长，我们被困死了
No results, captain. We're stuck tight.
史波克先生，状况如何？
Mr. Spock. Status?
飞船几乎被能量场包围了
The ship is almost completely encircled by the field.
它看起来是普通能量场，但是波长很特殊
It resembles a conventional force field, but on unusual wavelengths.
尽管它外表像人手
Despite its appearance, that of a human appendage,
它绝对不是生物组织，而是能量
it is definitely not living tissue. It is energy.
谢谢
Thank you.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
我们的前置牵引能量束，转换为喷射
Our forward tractor beams, adjust to repel.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
- 准备好了 - 启动
- Standing by. - Activate.
没有效果，舰长
Ineffective, captain.
看起来没有什么可以给我们反作用力
There doesn't seem to be anything to push against.
舰长，探测器57有新发现
Captain, a most curious development on Scanner 57.
我们一起来看一看，史波克先生
Let's all take a look at it, Mr. Spock.
启动屏幕，舰长
Screen on, captain.
3号频道有信号，长官
Activity on Hailing Channel 3, sir.
播放成音频，上尉
Put it on audio, lieutenant.
漫长的时间过去了
The aeons have passed,
历史即将重演
and what has been written has come about.
欢迎你们，我的爱子们，你们的地域在欢迎你们
You are most welcome, my beloved children. Your places await you.
- 回复频道，上尉 - 准备好了，已打开，长官
- Response frequency, lieutenant. - Calculated. Channel open, sir.
你们离开自己的土地勇敢的来到这里
You have left your plains and valleys and made this bold venture.
这一切早已注定
So it was in the beginning.
你们让我骄傲
You have made me proud.
现在你们可以休息了
Now you can rest.
我是詹姆士·T·寇克舰长，指挥联邦星舰进取号
This is Captain James T. Kirk, commanding the USS Enterprise.
- 请表明身份 - 我们要一起铭记
- Please identify yourself. - We shall remember together.
我们要一起饮用圣酒
We shall drink the sacramental wine.
管乐声响起
There shall be the music of the pipes.
漫长的等待结束了
The long wait has ended.
是你把飞船停下来的吗？
Are you responsible for stopping the ship?
是的
Yes,
我让风远离你们的帆
I caused the wind to withdraw from your sails.
把风还给我们，然后我才会继续跟你谈
Give it back, then we'll talk.
5000年过去了
It has been 5,000 years.
你们还没学会耐心吗？
Have you learned no patience in that time?
我不知道你是谁或是什么东西
I don't know who or what you are.
但是我必须警告你，我们有能力保护自己
But I must warn you, we have the power to defend ourselves.
如果你珍惜你的安全，就放开飞船
If you value your safety, release this ship.
你的脾气跟你的父亲们一样
You have the same fire. How like your fathers you are.
阿伽门农，赫克托，奥德修斯
Agamemnon, Hector, Odysseus...
别给我上历史课了，放开飞船
Never mind the history lesson, release the ship.
你会服从我
You will obey me,
不然我就握紧我的手，就像这样
lest I close my hand... thus.
外部压力上升中，舰长
External pressure building up, captain.
800gsc并还在增加
Eight hundred gsc and climbing.
抵消掉
Compensate.
1000gsc并继续增加
One thousand gsc and climbing.
越来越危险，舰长，我们承受不住
It's becoming critical, captain. We can't handle it.
好吧，不管你怎么办到的，停下来
All right, whatever you're doing, turn it off.
你赢了
You win.
压力没有了，舰长
Pressure's gone, captain.
舰体压力回到太空正常值
Space-normal on hull.
这是你们的第一个教训，记着它
That was your first lesson. Remember it.
寇克舰长，我邀请你和你的下属来见我
Captain Kirk, I invite you and your officers to join me.
但是不要带那一个
But do not bring that one,
耳朵尖尖那位
the one with the pointed ears.
他很像潘，我不喜欢潘
He is much like Pan, and Pan always bored me.
不要哭丧着脸
No sad faces.
这是高兴的时刻，不用害怕
This is a time to rejoice, not to fear.
你们回家了
You are returning home.
让你们的心准备歌唱吧
Let your hearts prepare to sing.
走吧，老骨头
Let's go, Bones.
- 你还能说话吗？ - 你确定这是个好主意吗，吉姆？
- You in good voice? - You sure it's wise, Jim?
如果我们不接受他的邀请
If we don't accept his invitation,
这艘飞船就会变成碎壳
we'll have a crushed eggshell where this ship used to be.
这人很罗嗦，不是吗？
Verbose, isn't he?
觉得被侮辱了吗，史波克？
Insulted, Spock?
羞辱只会通过感情表现出来
Insults are effective only where emotion is present.
那就好
Good.
我们一起对付他
We'll tackle him together.
我们已经知道问题所在
We already know the questions.
你是找到答案的最佳人选
You're the best man to find the answers.
三录仪
Tricorders.
- 我的任务是什么，医生？ - 你是人类考古专家，不是吗？
- What am I doing down here, doctor? - You're the A&A officer, aren't you?
考古学，人类学，古代文明
Archaeology, anthropology, ancient civilisations?
是的
Correct.
我们需要这些方面的专家
Well, we're going to need help in all those areas.
走吧
Come on.
我的孩子们，我等这一刻很久了
My children, long have I waited for this moment.
你们带来了那美丽富饶地球的回忆
The memories you bring of your lush and beautiful Earth.
绿草蓝天，牧民和羊群
Green fields and blue skies, the simple shepherds and their flocks.
你知道地球，你去过？
You know of Earth? You've been there?
曾经，我伸伸手，地球就会颤抖
Once I stretched out my hand and Earth trembled,
我呼口气，春天就来了
and I breathed upon it and spring returned.
你提到了阿伽门农，赫克托，奥德修斯
You mentioned Agamemnon, Hector, Odysseus.
你怎么知道他们的？
How do you know about them?
搜寻你们最古老的回忆
Search your most distant memories.
数千年前的回忆
Those of the thousands of years past,
我就在那里
and I am there.
你的父辈知道我，父辈的父辈也知道
Your fathers knew me, and your fathers' fathers.
我是阿波罗
I am Apollo.
- 那我就是俄国沙皇 - 契诃夫先生
- And I am the czar of all the Russias. - Mr. Chekov.
不好意思，舰长，我之前从没遇过神
I'm sorry, captain. I never met a god before.
- 你目前依然没有，仪表数据？ - 基本跟人相似，舰长
- And you haven't yet. Readings? - Simple humanoid, captain.
很明显不是这么简单
Evidently not so simple.
地球
Earth...
宇宙中最美丽女性的母亲
...mother of the most beautiful of women in the universe.
至少这还没变
That, at least, has not changed.
我很高兴
I am pleased.
是的，我的孩子们
Yes, my children.
宙斯，雅典娜，阿佛洛狄忒，阿耳忒弥斯
Zeus, Athena, Aphrodite, Artemis,
一群英勇的旅行者
a gallant band of travelers.
我们5000年前就知道你们的地球了
We knew your Earth well 5,000 of your years ago.
好了，我们应邀而来
All right, we're here at your invitation.
你能告诉我们你想干什么吗
Would you mind telling us what you want
不提那些希腊神话故事
without all the Olympian generalities?
你们不允许离开
You will not leave this place.
传输室
Transporter Room.
传输设备不会运转了
Your transportation device no longer functions.
进取号，回答
Enterprise, come in.
我也不允许那个设备运转，舰长
I will not permit that device to work either, captain.
你到底想要什么？
What is it you want?
你们会崇拜我，像你的父辈那样
You will worship me, as your fathers did before you.
你想当阿波罗，随便你
If you wanna play god and call yourself Apollo, that's your business.
- 但我们不会承认的，先生 - 我说了，你们要崇拜我
- But you're no god to us, mister. - I said, you would worship me.
- 你有很多要学的东西 - 你也是！
- And you've got a lot to learn. - And so have you!
让你们瞧瞧
Let the lesson begin.
欢迎来到奥林匹克山，寇克舰长
Welcome to Olympus, Captain Kirk.
史波克先生，联系不上登陆小组，所有频道都不通
Mr. Spock, I can't contact the landing party. All frequencies are jammed.
- 全力接通 - 是的，长官
- Try to break through. - Aye, sir.
- 传输装置？ - 不管用了
- Transporter and communications? - Inefficient.
苏鲁先生，把所有动力设备调到最大功率
Mr. Sulu, rig all transmission circuits for maximum power generation.
计算逆转能量罩极性需要的能量
Compute for reversal of polarity of the field around the ship.
马上，长官
Working, sir.
对星球做全面扫描
I want a complete sensor scan of the planet.
- 是的，长官 - 定位所有生命物
- Aye, sir. - Locate all life forms.
我要知道下面发生了什么
I wanna know what's going on down there.
制造幻想，真厉害
To coin a phrase, fascinating.
分析
Analysis.
帕拉马斯上尉，你对阿波罗知道多少？
Lieutenant Palamas, what do you know about Apollo?
阿波罗，阿耳忒弥斯的双胞兄弟
Apollo, twin brother of Artemis,
宙斯和凡人勒托之子
son of the god Zeus and Leto, a mortal.
他是掌管光和纯净之神
He was the god of light and purity.
他精于弓箭和竖琴
He was skilled in the bow and the lyre.
那这个东西？
And this thing?
明显他对地球有了解
Obviously, he has some knowledge of Earth.
他对典故的了解和这里的外貌
His classical references and the appearance of all this.
我认为这里是专为我们设计的，老骨头？
I think the appearance of all this is for our benefit. Bones?
在检查数据前我不好说什么
Well, I can't say much until I check out these readings.
他看起来是人，当然这说明不了什么
He looks human, but of course that doesn't mean a thing.
不管他是什么，他看起来控制了很高的科技
Whatever he is, sir, he seems to control a remarkable technology.
是能量，做那种动作需要很大的能量
Power is what he controls. You can't do tricks like that without energy.
好吧，什么能量，在哪里？
Fine, but what power? Where is it?
用三录仪检查周围，找到能量源
Scout around with your tricorders. Find the source of that power.
- 老骨头 - 嗯？
- Bones. - Yeah?
老骨头，我在想，如果5000年前
Bones, I wonder if 5,000 years ago...
- 你有个理论？ - 我有个想法
- You have a theory? - I have an idea.
要是他真是阿波罗呢？
What if he is really Apollo?
- 什么？ - 舰长？
- What? - Captain?
我想从你们那得到属于我的东西
I want from you that which is rightfully mine.
忠诚，贡品，和崇拜
Your loyalty, your tribute and your worship.
那我们能得到什么？
May I ask what you offer in exchange for this worship?
天堂里的生活
Life in paradise,
跟几千年前一样，简单而愉快的生活
as simple and as pleasureful as it was those thousands of years ago
就像在那遥远的地球上一样
on that beautiful planet so far away.
阿波罗
Apollo...
我们很乐意跟你交谈
...we're willing to talk,
但是我们不对所有
but you'll find we don't bow to every creature
能玩戏法的生物屈膝
who happens to have a bag of tricks.
阿伽门农就跟你一样，还有海格力斯
Agamemnon was one such as you. And Hercules.
自傲又无礼
Pride and arrogance.
他们藐视我，直到我发怒
They defied me until they felt my wrath.
我想告诉你，我们也会发怒的
I would like to point out that we are quite capable of some wrath ourselves.
我有430人在飞船上
I have 430 people on that ship up there.
不，舰长，他们是我的
No, you do not, captain. They are mine.
挽救，珍惜，或者毁灭，都在我一念间
To save, to cherish, or to destroy at my will.
但是为什么？我不明白你所说的一切
But why? What you've said so far makes no sense at all.
真像阿佛洛狄忒和雅典娜
How like Aphrodite and Athena.
美丽，优雅
The beauty, grace.
你像是个聪明的女人
You seem wise for a woman.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 帕拉马斯上尉
- What is your name? - Lieutenant Palamas.
我是说你的名字
I mean your name.
卡洛琳
Carolyn.
是的，你真美
Yes. You are beautiful.
你有当爱神的资格
You would do Aphrodite credit.
我会告诉你很多故事，有关勇气和爱
I will tell you a thousand tales, stories of courage and love.
你会知道怎样当好女神
You will know what it is to be a goddess.
别惹她
Leave her alone!
你反对？
You protest?
- 你危险了 - 你也一样
- You risk much. - And so do you.
史考特
Scotty.
很厉害，你怎么做到的？
Very impressive. How'd you do it?
我对这些争论感到厌倦了
I've grown weary of discussion and argument.
舰长，这枪
Captain, the phasers.
所有部件都融化了
All the working parts are fused.
这些玩具都不会有用的
None of your toys will function.
是的，你真美
Yes, you are a beauty.
但是跟阿耳忒弥斯一样
But like Artemis,
拉弓的手臂要露出来
the bow arm should be bare.
啊，真美
Oh, it's beautiful.
是的
Yes.
- 来吧 - 她不会跟你走的
- Come. - She's not going with you.
他需要控制自己的脾气
He shall learn the discipline of the temple.
你们也一样
So shall you all.
来吧
Come.
没事的，舰长，我会跟他走
It's all right, captain. I'll go.
不用害怕
Without fear.
她很合适
She is fit indeed.
老骨头，他怎样？
Bones, how is he?
晕过去了，但正在恢复，我不确定让她过去是个好主意
Stunned, but coming around. I'm not sure it's wise to let her go off like that.
想阻止他很难
He would have been rather difficult to stop.
你见了他有多善变，前一分钟很友善，马上就发怒
You saw how capricious he is. Benevolent one minute, angry the next.
走错一步，他就会杀了她
One wrong move from her and he could kill her.
契诃夫先生，我觉得你最好继续调查
Mr. Chekov, I think you'd better continue your investigation.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
你感觉怎样，史考特
Well, how do you feel, Scotty?
全身都疼
I am tingling all over.
- 他带她走了吗？ - 看起来是的
- Did he take her with him? - It would seem so.
舰长，我们必须阻止他，他想占有她
Captain, we've got to stop him. He wants her.
- 他看她的眼神 - 史考特先生！
- The way he looked at her... - Mr. Scott!
我理解你的担心，但是她自愿而去
I understand your concern over her, but she volunteered to go with him.
希望她是去找到更多信息，她在做她的工作
Hopefully, to find out more. She's doing her job.
我觉得你也该做你的工作了
I think it's about time you started doing yours.
我们必须找到他的能量源
We've got to find out the source of his power.
你有一个三录仪，好好利用，如果你没什么问题
You've got a tricorder. Use it, if you're able to.
- 我还行，长官 - 还有一件事
- I'm able, sir. - And one more thing.
没我命令不许再对阿波罗行动
I want no more unauthorized action against Apollo or whatever he is.
- 这是命令 - 是，长官
- That's an order. - Aye, aye, sir.
你个倔驴，你会没命的
Besides, you stiff-necked thistlehead, you could have gotten yourself killed.
知道了
Aye.
- 史考特不相信神 - 阿波罗不是神
- Scotty doesn't believe in gods. - Apollo's no god.
但是
But...
他可能曾经被当成神
...he could have been taken for one, though, once.
比如5000年前
Say 5,000 years ago,
高度文明的宇宙航行者来到地球
a highly sophisticated group of space travelers landed on Earth
在地中海附近
around the Mediterranean.
是啊
Yes.
对古希腊那些单纯的牧民和部落来说
To the simple shepherds and tribesmen of early Greece,
他们会被当成神
creatures like that would have been gods.
尤其是他们能随意变形
Especially if they had the power to alter their form at will
并控制强大的能量
and command great energy.
事实上，他们只会被当成神
In fact, they couldn't have been taken for anything else.
准备好逆转极性了吗，苏鲁先生？
Ready to reverse polarity, Mr. Sulu?
准备好了，长官
Computed and standing by to generate, sir.
启动所有单元
Activate all units.
不妙，史波克先生，根本无效
No good, Mr. Spock. We didn't even faze it.
- 我们还是动弹不了 - 取消，苏鲁先生
- We're still locked tight. - Cut power, Mr. Sulu.
上尉，我们必须重新跟着陆人员建立联系
Lieutenant, we must restore communications with the landing party.
正在想办法，长官，但是似乎没用
Well, I'm working, sir, but I can't do anything with this.
我也许可以建立一个亚空间旁路
Well, I might be able to rig up a subspace bypass circuit.
很好，就那样，探测器报告，卡尔先生
Good, do so. Sensor report, Mr. Kyle.
已找到着陆人员，长官
I've located the landing party, sir.
其中一个似乎离开了
But one of them seems separated from the other four.
阿波罗呢？
And Apollo?
我只找到了我们的人的信号
I've just picked up readings for our own people.
史波克先生，有情况
Mr. Spock, here's something.
这星球上似乎有放射性能量脉冲
There seems to be a radiated energy pulsation coming from the planet.
- 还没弄清楚是什么，长官 - 源自哪里？
- I don't know what it is, sir. - Origin?
还找不到，长官
I can't seem to pinpoint it, sir.
苏鲁先生，我建议，如果你找不到
I would suggest, Mr. Sulu, that if you cannot find out
能量源在哪里，那就找到它不在哪里
where the power source is, you should find out where it is not.
用排除法
A simple process of elimination.
对整个星球吗，长官？
The whole planet, sir?
是的
Yes, sir, the whole planet.
真动人
It's lovely.
我也认识其他女人，达芙妮，卡珊德拉
I've known other women, Daphne, Cassandra.
但你是最美的
But none more beautiful than you.
- 你害怕我吗？ - 害怕？
- Are you frightened of me? - Frightened?
不，我不害怕
No, I don't think so.
当然，一般女孩不会跟你这样的走在一起
Of course, a girl doesn't go walking with a...
跟一个神？
A god?
好吧，你每天换一个女伴
All right. A god every day.
其他人怎样了？阿耳忒弥斯，赫拉？
What happened to the others? Artemis, Hera?
他们都随风而去了
They returned to the cosmos on the wings of the wind.
- 他们死了？ - 不是
- You mean they died? - No.
不是你理解的那种死亡
Not as you understand it.
我们神是不朽的
We're immortal, we gods.
但是地球变了
But the Earth changed.
你的父辈们变了
Your fathers changed.
他们叛离了我们，把我们当成了回忆
They turned away until we were only memories.
我们无法只活在别人的回忆里
A god cannot survive as a memory.
我们需要爱，敬仰和崇拜
We need love, admiration, worship,
就像你需要食物
as you need food.
你真的觉得你是神吗？
You really think you're a god?
从现实意义说，我们的确曾经是神
In a real sense, we were gods.
我们掌握生死
We had the power of life and death.
我们可以从奥林匹克山毁灭人类
We could have struck out from Olympus and destroyed.
但我们不愿意那样做
We have no wish to destroy.
所以我们回家了
So we came home again.
那是个没有跟随者的地方
It was an empty place without worshippers.
但是我们没有力气继续再离开了
But we had no strength to leave.
所以我们一直等待着
So we waited, all of us.
在漫长的岁月里
Through the long years.
但你说其他人没有死
But you said the others didn't die.
就算神，也有消亡的一天
Even for a god, there's a point of no return.
赫拉最先走了
Hera was first.
她站在神庙前，慢慢消亡在风中
She stood in front of the temple and spread herself upon the wind.
越来越稀薄
Thinner and thinner,
最后只剩下风
until only the wind remained.
但我坚信你们会来
But I knew you would come.
你们这些奋斗不息，熙熙攘攘又无比勇敢的人类
You striving, bickering, foolishly brave humans.
我早知道你们有一天会来
I knew you would come to the stars one day.
在所有神中，只有我坚信并等待着
Of all the gods, I knew and I waited.
等待你的到来，等待你坐在我身边
Waited for you to come and sit by my side.
我不理解
I don't understand.
就算5000年前
Even 5,000 years ago,
神也会爱上凡人，守护凡人
the gods took mortals to them to love, to care for.
就像宙斯爱上了勒托，我的母亲
Like Zeus took Leto, my mother.
我们是有激情的神
We were gods of passion,
有爱的神
of love.
这儿有周期性的仪器显示
There is a repeated occurrence of registrations.
一种规则的放射性能量脉动
A regular pulsating pattern of radiated energy.
毫无疑问，一个巨大的能量场
Unquestionably, an immensely powerful field of energy
在这周围的某个地方产生着
is being generated around here somewhere,
但是我们就是找不到
but we're having difficulty focusing on it.
阿波罗能轻易找到能量并使用它，史考特先生
Apollo has no difficulty focusing. He taps that energy, Mr. Scott.
长官，有的生物能产生并操纵能量
Sir, some creatures can generate and control energy
并且不对自身产生危害
with no harm to themselves.
地球上的电鳗，安托斯四号上的巨型干蠕虫
The electric eel on Earth, the giant dry-worm of Antos IV.
- 松软的… - 不要搬出整个百科全书，契诃夫
- The fluffy... - Not the whole encyclopaedia, Chekov.
舰长要求提供完整信息
The captain requires complete information.
史波克把这孩子带坏了，吉姆
Spock's contaminating this boy, Jim.
你是在说
Are you suggesting that he,
阿波罗
Apollo,
汲取这能量流并通过身体传导？
taps the flow of energy and channels it through his body?
这是最可能的情况，长官
That would seem most likely, sir.
契诃夫先生，你这个星期的工钱有了
Mr. Chekov, I think you've earned your pay for the week.
但是能量源在哪呢？
But where is the source of that power?
那就是我们当前最要紧的事
Number one on our list of things to do.
你能说点有用的吗？
Is that all you have to offer?
好吧，还有我对他身体状况的判断
Yes, except my estimation for his physical condition.
尽管他会变很多戏法，他看起来很普通
In spite of Apollo's bag of tricks, he comes up essentially normal
只有少数地方跟人类不同
with just a few variations.
但他胸前有个额外的器官，我猜不到是什么
However, there's an extra organ in his chest I can't even make a guess about.
- 老骨头，会不会… - 吉姆
- Bones, is it possible..? - Jim.
帕拉马斯上尉去哪了？
Where's Lieutenant Palamas?
她不关你的事
She is no longer of any concern to you.
你这个嗜血的撒拉逊人
You bloodthirsty Saracen,
- 你把她怎么了？ - 史考特！史考特！
- what have you done with her? - Scotty! Scotty!
情况不秒，严重撞击
Not good. Severe shock.
好吧，先生
All right, mister.
你想要崇拜者是吧？你先有了敌人
You wanted worshippers? You've got enemies.
你想要我们跪倒…
You want us to bow down...
你要学习纪律，你要学习…
You will learn discipline. You will learn...
契诃夫，帮个手
Chekov, give me a hand.
- 去照顾史考特 - 你还好吗，舰长？
- Take care of Scotty. - Are you all right, captain?
- 阿波罗呢？ - 他又消失了
- Where's Apollo? - He disappeared again,
就像那个俄国故事里的猫
like the cat in that Russian story.
你是说那个英国故事吧，柴郡猫？
Don't you mean the English story, the Cheshire cat?
- 柴郡？不，长官，好像是明斯克… - 好啦，好吧
- Cheshire? No, sir. Minsk, perhaps... - All right. All right. All right.
长官，我注意到了一些东西
Sir, there is something I noticed.
阿波罗消失的时候看起来很奇怪
Apollo looked very strange when he disappeared.
很疲倦或者说痛苦，我不知道这信息有用没
Tired or in pain. I don't know if it means anything.
很好，契科夫先生，那可能很有用
Very good, Mr. Chekov. That might very well mean something.
- 你感觉怎样？ - 我的胳膊动不了
- How do you feel? - I can't get my arm to move.
某种神经伤害
Some neural damage.
- 我们必须离开这儿 - 怎么离开？
- We've got to get out of here. - How?
我们假设
How? Let's assume that
5000年前
5,000 years ago,
像阿波罗这样的生物的确去过地球
creatures like our friend, Apollo, did indeed visit Earth,
并构成了古希腊神话的基础
and formed the basis of the Greek classic myths.
- 这很合理 - 大多数神话都有事实基础
- It makes sense. - Most mythology has its basis in fact.
如果我记得没错，神在使用能量后
Now, if I remember my ancient legends, the gods, after expending energy,
需要休息，像我们人类一样
required rest, even as we humans.
在攻击你和史考特之后
And Apollo's gone.
阿波罗离开了
After attacking you and Mr. Scott.
你觉得他是不是躲在哪儿充能
You think maybe he's off somewhere recharging his energy cells?
就是那样
Something like that.
别忘了，他还要维护进取号外面的能量场
Remember, he's keeping a force field on the ship
现在他又在这儿消耗能量
and he's expending energy down here.
你说他消失的时候看起来痛苦而疲倦
You said he looked pained and tired when he disappeared.
如果我们能让他筋疲力尽，可能会奏效
If we can wear him out, overwork him, that might do it.
但是问题是要让他筋疲力竭很可能让我们没命
The trouble with overworking him is that it can get us killed.
如果我们激怒他，让他攻击我们中的一个
If we can provoke him so that he strikes one of us again,
那他可能会精疲力尽，其余人就能制服他
there's a chance that he'll be drained enough, the rest of us can jump him.
- 我还是想说那我们可能会没命 - 不是所有的人，老骨头
- I still say it can get us killed. - Not all of us, Bones.
他回来的时候，我们必须抓住这个机会
When he comes back, it's a chance we'll have to take.
报告进展
Progress report.
我正在建立旁路连接，长官
I'm connecting the bypass circuit now, sir.
可能还需要半个小时
It should take another half hour.
分秒必争，上尉
Speed is essential, lieutenant.
史波克先生，我很多年没做过这类工作了
Mr. Spock, I haven't done anything like this in years.
要是没处理好，我们整个通讯系统就完了
If it isn't done just right, I could blow the entire communications system.
这是细活，长官
It's very delicate work, sir.
你是完成这项工作的最佳人选，乌乎拉小姐
I can think of no one better equipped to handle it, Miss Uhura.
- 请继续吧 - 好的，长官，马上
- Please proceed. - Yes, sir. Right away.
进展如何，苏鲁先生？
Progress, Mr. Sulu?
区域1到25制图并检查完毕
Sectors 1 through 25 charted and examined.
这些区域不可能有能量源
No chance at all of power originating in those areas.
- 继续搜查 - 是长官，正在搜索26区14B
- Continue the search. - Aye, sir. 14B by 26 index.
- 卡尔先生？ - 是，长官
- Mr. Kyle? - Yes, sir.
我们没办法挣脱能量场
We're unable to break completely loose from this force field,
但我们可能可以在上面打几个洞
but we might be able to punch some holes through it.
- 为什么，长官？ - 这样就可以攻击了
- What for, sir? - To shoot through.
这也可能解决乌乎拉上尉的通讯问题
It might also relieve Lieutenant Uhura's communications problem.
把这些方程拿去核电实验室
You'll take these equations to the nuclear electronics lab.
我想要他们想办法
I want them to work on the problem
在选定区域消除能量场
of negating the force field in selected areas.
用上所有引擎的功率
Now, it might be done by generating a strong pinpoint charge of M-rays
将特定波长的M射线聚集起来
on some of these selected wavelengths and tying them in
说不定能行得通
with the combined output of all our engines.
马上去办，长官
Right away, sir.
过来
Come here.
我知道你们想逃，没用的
I know you're trying to escape me. It's useless.
我知道你们做的所有事
I know everything you do.
我已经对你们仁慈过了
I tried to be compassionate toward your kind.
你对我们一无所知，你只知道我们的远祖
You know nothing about our kind, you know only our remote ancestors
你可以吓坏我们的远祖，但吓不倒我们
who trembled before your tricks. Your tricks don't frighten us. Neither do you.
5000年来我们进步很多
We've come a long way in 5,000 years.
但是你们本质没变
But you're still of the same nature.
我挥挥手就能灭掉你们
I could sweep you out of existence
又或是让你们复活
with a wave of my hand and bring you back again.
我可掌握生死
I can give life or death.
这样的神你们还不满意？
What else does mankind demand of its gods?
人类不需要神明
Mankind has no need for gods.
我们已经找到寄托了
We find the one quite adequate.
不要争辩，凡人
We shall not debate, mortal.
我可以给你们永恒的安宁快乐，像古时候一样
I offer you eternal rest and happiness according to the ancient ways.
我只需要一点点回报
I ask little in return.
但是我坚持我要的东西
But what I ask for, I insist upon.
过来
Approach me.
我说靠过来
I said approach me!
我们忙着呢，照顾好女性
We're busy. Look after the girl.
你们要采集月桂树叶，点亮古老的火焰
You will gather laurel leaves. Light the ancient fires.
杀一只鹿，对我供奉
Kill a deer. Make your sacrifices to me!
- 阿波罗的命令！ - 行动！
- Apollo has spoken! - Go!
采集月桂叶，你在开玩笑吧
Gather laurel leaves, you must be joking.
杀一只鹿，那是我听过的最可笑的事
Kill a deer! That's the funniest thing I ever heard.
继续！
Go ahead!
- 停下来 - 上尉，退后！
- Stop. - Lieutenant, get back!
你们要为你们的傲慢负责
You shall reap the rewards of your insolence!
- 我们厌倦了你伪善的一套 - 凡人，你罪有应得
- We're tired of your phoney fireworks. - Mortal, you have earned this!
- 不，不要 - 上尉，上尉！
- No, don't. - Lieutenant. Lieutenant!
一个父亲不会伤害自己的孩子
A father doesn't destroy his children.
你说过你绅士而体贴
You said you were gentle and understanding.
- 上尉！ - 要是你伤害了他们
- Lieutenant! - How can they worship you
- 他们怎么会崇拜你？ - 上尉
- if you hurt them? - Lieutenant.
阿波罗，求你了，你那么博爱
Apollo, please. You know so much of love.
求你不要伤害他们
Please don't hurt them.
求你了
Please.
我饶过你
I shall be lenient with you
为了她
for her sake.
安排飞船上的人登陆
You will make plans to bring the rest of your people down.
让匠人别忘了带工具
Be sure your artisans bring tools.
你们会需要住所
You will need homes.
那你会提供羊群，我们吹奏的长笛
And you will supply the herds of sheep and the pipes we will play
还有做衣物的兽皮吗？
and the simple skins we'll wear for clothes?
你们需要把飞船拆掉作为供给
You will dismantle your ship for the supplies you need.
我会把剩下的空壳子碾碎
And I'll crush its empty hull.
我对你们太过耐心了
I have been too patient.
不会再这样了
I shall be patient no longer.
舰长，我们必须做点什么
Captain, we've got to do something.
在那位勇敢的女士挽救我们前一切顺利
We were doing something until our brave lady stepped in and saved us.
- 还有别的好主意吗，吉姆？ - 是的，有一个
- Got any more good ideas, Jim? - Yes, I have.
还有一个，取决于我们的上尉是否忠诚，如果她叛变
One more, and it depends on the lieutenant's loyalty. If she fails us,
我们最好去习惯牧羊的生活吧
we'd better get used to herding goats.
愚蠢的人们
Fools.
我提供给他们想都不敢想的东西
I offer them more than they could know.
不仅仅是一个世界，而是方方面面
Not just a world, but all that makes it up.
人类认为他们进步了
Man thinks he's progressed.
他们错了，他们只是忘掉了那些给予生命意义的东西
They're wrong. He's merely forgotten those things which gave life meaning.
你们都会被照料，被看护，幸福地活着
You'll all be provided for, cared for, happy.
这个宇宙有自己的规则
There is an order of things in this universe.
你的种族否定它，我来重建它
Your species has denied it. I come to restore it.
而你
And for you,
因为你敏锐的理解能力
because you have the sensitivity to understand,
我将给你做梦都想不到的一切
I offer you more than your wildest dreams have ever imagined.
你会成为神明一族的母亲
You'll become the mother of a new race of gods.
你将鼓舞宇宙，所有男人都会崇拜你
You'll inspire the universe. All men will revere you,
你会像一个真正的神一样
almost as a god yourself.
我会爱你到时间的尽头
And I shall love you for time without end,
天涯海角
worlds without end.
你让我完整，相反亦然
You shall complete me, and I you.
寇克呼叫进取号，进取号，回答
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in. Enterprise, come in.
寇克呼叫进取号，回答
Kirk to Enterprise, come in.
- 寇克呼叫… - 卡洛琳！
- Kirk to... - Carolyn!
- 她发生什么了？ - 史考特，我会弄明白的
- What's happened to her? - Scotty, I'll find out.
如果我帮忙…
Perhaps if I assisted...
- 你多大了？ - 22，长官
- How old are you? - Twenty-two, sir.
那还是我来吧
Then I'd better handle it.
- 你还好吗？ - 是的，我还好
- You all right? - Oh, yes, I'm all right.
我有个消息带给你
I have a message for you.
过来这边说话
Come over there.
说吧？
Well?
他希望我们和平的生活
He wants us to live in peace.
他想要为我们提供一切
He wants to provide for us.
他会给我们一切我们想要的东西，而且他有能力办到
He'll give us everything we ever wanted. And he can do it too.
好了，你该从奥林匹克梦里醒来了
All right, you can come down from Mount Olympus now.
你还有工作要做
You've got work to do.
- 我不明白 - 他依靠爱，崇拜，关注而生
- I don't understand. - He thrives on love, worship, attention.
- 是的 - 我们不能让他得逞
- Yes. - We can't give him that worship.
我们都不要崇拜他，尤其是你
None of us can. Especially you.
什么？
What?
藐视他，拒绝他
Spurn him. Reject him.
你必须这样做
You must.
- 你对他很特别 - 是的
- You're special to him. - Yes.
我爱他
I love him.
上尉
Lieutenant,
我们的生命，这里和船上的人
all our lives, here and on the ship,
都靠你了
depend on you.
- 不，不是靠我 - 是靠你，上尉
- No, not on me. - On you, lieutenant.
拒绝他我们还有机会拯救自己，接受他
Reject him and we have a chance to save ourselves. Accept him
那么你就让我们变成奴隶，根本就是奴隶
and you condemn all of us to slavery, nothing less than slavery.
我们在这儿永远也得不到帮助了，或者你觉得
We might never get help this far out. Or perhaps the thought
永远屈膝，喂羊是很不错的生活
of spending an eternity bending knee and tending sheep appeals to you.
噢，但你不理解
Oh, but you don't understand.
他很和蔼，他想要为我们好
He's kind and he wants the best for us.
并且他那么孤独
And he's so lonely.
你的要求会伤他心的
What you ask would break his heart.
我怎么能那样做？
Now, how can I?
给我你的手，你的手
Give me your hand. Your hand.
感受这个
Now, feel that.
手心和手心
Human flesh against human flesh.
我们是同类
We're the same.
共同的历史，文化遗产和生活
We share the same history, the same heritage, the same lives.
我们联系在一起
We're tied together beyond any untying.
男人或是女人，没有区别，我们都是人类
Man or woman, it makes no difference. We're human.
我们无法分离，你知道该怎么做了吗
We couldn't escape from each other if we wanted to. That's how you do it.
记住我们是谁，我们是人类
By remembering who and what you are. A bit of flesh and blood
在无边宇宙中漫游的血肉之躯
afloat in a universe without end.
在这儿，唯一属于你的
And the only thing that's truly yours
就是其余的人类
is the rest of humanity.
那就是我们的责任，你明白我的意思吗？
That's where our duty lies. Do you understand me?
是的
Yes.
是的，我明白
Yes, I understand.
他在呼唤我
He's calling me.
上尉
Lieutenant,
你身负命令和你的义务
you have your orders and your duty.
是的，长官，命令和责任
Yes, sir, my orders and my duty.
我觉得我们可以试试了，长官
I think we can try it now, sir.
进取号呼叫寇克舰长
Enterprise to Captain Kirk.
- 进取号呼叫寇克舰长，回答 - 寇克在此
- Enterprise to Captain Kirk. Come in. - Kirk here.
我是史波克，舰长
Spock here, captain.
我们已经在星球表面定位到一个能量源
We've pinpointed a power source on the planet's surface
看起来跟能量场有关
which seems to have something to do with the force field.
你附近有什么建筑吗？
Is there a structure of some sort near you?
- 是的，史波克先生 - 那能量就来自那里
- There is, indeed, Mr. Spock. - The power emanates from there.
很好，那你怎么对付能量场？
Very good. How are you doing on the force field?
我们可以让它部分失效，制造缺口
We can negate sections of it, creating openings
我们就可以使用相位炮组了
through which we can fire our phaser banks.
很好，那应该能行
Well, that ought to do it.
让苏鲁先生将所有相位炮锁定在那个建筑上
Have Mr. Sulu lock all phaser banks onto the structure.
听我号令开火停火，我们就在附近
Fire on my order only and cut it fine. We'll be standing nearby.
舰长
Captain,
我建议你们离远点
I would recommend a discreet distance.
我很想听你的史波克，但我们没待在一起
I'd love to oblige you, Mr. Spock, but we're not all together.
况且我们还要对付阿波罗
Besides we have Apollo to deal with.
如果那建筑的确是他的能量源
If that structure is the source of his power,
在摧毁建筑时得找到阿波罗的位置
I wanna know where he is when we attack it.
寇克完毕
Kirk out.
老骨头，你觉得阿波罗胸前的神秘器官
Bones, do you think that mysterious organ in Apollo's chest
是不是跟能量传导有关？
has something to do with the transmission of energy?
除此之外，我想不到其他作用
It doesn't serve any other purpose I know of.
舰长，我们必须等卡洛琳回来
Captain, we've got to wait until Carolyn comes back
再对神庙开火
before we fire on the temple.
如果他被袭击了，会对卡洛琳做什么？
We don't know what would happen to her if he was suddenly attacked.
- 她可能会被杀掉 - 是的，我知道
- She might get killed. - Yes, I know.
我知道，史考特，我们会等的
I know, Scotty. We'll wait.
我必须要说，阿波罗
I must say, Apollo,
你模仿人类的能力很强
the way you ape human behaviour is remarkable.
但我还要知道另外一些事
But there are some other things I must know.
你的进化模式和社会发展模式
Your evolutionary patterns and your social development.
我的什么？
My what?
我确信它们也很独特
I'm sure they're unique.
我以前从没遇过你这样的物种
I've never encountered a specimen like you before.
我是阿波罗，我选中了你
I am Apollo. I've chosen you.
为此我感到高兴，但是我必须开始工作了
But I'm sure that's very flattering, but I must get on with my work now.
- 你的工作？ - 我是个科学家
- Your work? - I'm a scientist.
我的专长是古代文明，遗址和神话
My particular speciality is ancient civilisations, relics and myths.
你明白我一直都只是在研究你吧
Why, surely you know I've only been studying you.
我不相信，你是爱我的
I don't believe it. You love me.
爱你？
Love you?
理智点吧
Be logical.
我不是那种害怕你的牧羊人
I'm not some simple shepherdess you can awe.
我对你的爱跟我爱一种新的…
Why, I could no more love you than I could love a new species of...
细菌一样
...bacteria.
卡洛琳，我不允许你离开
Carolyn, I forbid you to go.
我命令你留下
I order you to stay.
这就是你对女性吸引力的秘密吗？
Is that the secret of your power over women?
是你丢出的闪电吗？
The thunderbolts you throw?
那是什么？
What the devil is that?
- 寇克在此 - 史波克在此，舰长
- Kirk here. - Spock, captain.
探测器显示你的区域有大气变化
Sensors are picking up an atmospheric disturbance in your area.
相位炮待命，史波克听我号令开火，寇克完毕
Stand by your phasers, Mr. Spock. Prepare to fire on my signal. Kirk out.
我们必须去找到她
We've got to go and find her.
他回来的时候我们必须在这儿
We've gotta be here when he comes back.
- 但是如果他不回来呢？如果…？ - 史考特，坚持住
- But what if he doesn't? What if..? - Scotty, just hold on.
- 不要！ - 舰长
- No! - Captain.
好吧
All right.
神庙是他的能量源，让我们把他吸引回来，找掩护
The temple is his power source. Let's bring him back to it. Get to cover.
史波克先生，开火
Mr. Spock, fire those phasers.
- 舰长，你太近了 - 开火，这是命令
- Captain, you're too close. - Fire those phasers. That's an order.
所有相位炮组，开火
All phaser banks, fire.
不！停下！
No! Stop!
我说了，停下！
Stop, I say!
- 所有相位炮，保持开火 - 增加防护罩功率
- All phaser banks, maintain firing rate. - More power to the shields.
停下！
Stop!
史考特！
Scotty!
我说了，停下！
Stop, I say!
我命令你停下！
I command it!
- 所有相位炮，继续开火 - 正在进行中，长官
- All banks, maintain firing rate. - Maintaining, sir.
停下！
Stop!
我本可以珍惜你们，照顾你们
I would have cherished you, cared for you.
我本可以像父亲爱孩子一样爱你们
I would have loved you as a father loves his children.
我要求得太多了吗？
Did I ask so much?
我们已经比你先进
We've outgrown you.
我们无法满足你的要求
You asked for something we can no longer give.
卡洛琳
Carolyn,
我爱过你
I loved you.
我本可以让你成为女神
I would have made a goddess of you.
我对你敞开了心扉
I've shown you my open heart.
看看你做了什么
See what you've done to me.
宙斯
Zeus,
赫耳墨斯，赫拉
Hermes, Hera,
阿佛洛狄忒
Aphrodite,
你们是对的
you were right.
雅典娜
Athena,
你是对的
you were right.
我们的时代过去了
The time has passed.
神明被抛弃了
There is no room for gods.
原谅我吧，老朋友们
Forgive me, my old friends.
带我走吧
Take me.
- 我希望我们不必如此 - 我也是
- I wish we hadn't had to do this. - So do I.
他们曾给我们那么多
They gave us so much.
希腊文明，我们很多的文化和哲学
The Greek civilisation, much of our culture and philosophy,
都来自对他们的崇拜
came from the worship of those beings.
某种意义上说，他们开启了黄金时代
In a way, they began the golden age.
我在想，去采集一些月桂叶
Would it have hurt us, I wonder,
也不是什么大事
just to have gathered a few laurel leaves?
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/